I'm
the core tenets of Confucianism really
is do your job don't be a dick. Yeah,
that's right. You didn't [__] think
that this is what we'd be doing today,
huh?
>> [clears throat]
>> Oh, [__]
Yes.
We're going to talk about Confucius and
we're going to talk about his theorized
favorite food Chinese ragout Chinese
spaghetti and meat sauce. As you can see
I got a haircut. I washed my apron and
I'm going to bring out a bunch of gay
little cups to me's on plus all of my
ingredients because we are talking about
Confucius. Confucius [music]
is probably one of the most persnickety
[__] people on earth. If you were kind
you could say that he was a precocious
man, but if you were normal you would
say that he sounded like a Michelin
inspector [music] / hipster / OCD /
autistic
broke high [music] school teacher
homeless person couldn't hold down a job
and very [__] straight guy. The most
heterosexual incel [__] on earth, but
his teachings did create some good and
today we're going to talk to you about
my understanding
of Confucius's teachings, what might be
history, what might be theory, what
might be myth, the good, the bad, the
otherwise and how it pertains to
spaghetti and meat sauce. [music] Let's
start with who he was. His name was Kong
Qiu. His courtesy name was Zhongni. A
little bit of information. When someone
asks oh for your surname in Chinese the
polite way of saying it even in modern
[music] Chinese is ni xing shen me. Your
ming is the name that you were given
after you were born. It's really [__]
rude back then to call someone by their
full ass name, right? If you wanted to
what up Kong Qiu? Like that's not okay.
You don't do that. Even in today it's
[__] weird, which is why when we
introduce each other we usually use a
nickname. We rarely rarely ever would
say like hey Kohaku." It's odd. Even my
name when it's short. They don't even My
colleagues do not call me Kohaku. He was
born to an old aristocrat right when
their family went broke. The only reason
he existed was literally to inherit his
dad's [__] So, his dad, Konghu,
had like 9 million billion daughters.
Then he was like, "I don't want to give
these [__]
So, he made a son. And the story is that
she prayed at Mount Ni, hence the name
Ni. And a heron, a chilling, just
brought him down and burst him into the
world. So, this is the myth. He's
already a mythical creature. Like I
said, Kongzi was a precocious child. And
the myth goes that he didn't even play
with toys because he wanted to honor his
father. Instead, he practiced rituals
and pretend funerals. So, he just played
jiajia and cosplayed a very literate man
while burning things and sacrificing and
all that. So, this is already not a good
precursor to what kind of adult he's
going to be. He was probably 60, 70, 80
years old, and he was huge. He was a
imba imba dude, according to legend. A
big, juicy Shandong boy. Now, despite
being born into a broke minor noble
family, he was still a noble. And nobles
were taught the six arts of nobility.
Li, rituals and etiquette. So, like, how
to dress, how to behave, how to drink
your ah, right? Like, which hand goes
over which hand, distances to stand,
things to say, how to say hello. Oh, by
the way, for any white people, ABCs, or
kung fu movie fans out there, never
[__] do this. This doesn't exist.
This is not a [music] real thing. If
you're a man, it's left hand over right
fist. Kind of like the history behind
why you drive [music] on the right side
of the road. I could [__] you up,
but I'm not going to [music] cuz I'm
civilized.
>> [laughter]
>> That's what that means.
I'mma knock your [__] teeth out,
but I'm choosing not to cuz I went to
school. [laughter]
Shu, literature, the reading words. Shu,
maths, arithmetics. And then it gets
kind of weird. Yeah, music. But this was
like 2,500 years ago. There wasn't
really banger music. There wasn't pop
music where people go
"I'm Chinese." "Ooh, ooh."
It was like music was a personal thing.
You used it as a way of meditating, to
learn harmony through orderly learning
of an art. So music was like playing a
ching and trying to figure out the
universe through plucking strings. And
then there was shua, which is
shua, archery. Because archery was also
a form of meditation, but it was like
meditation with murder involved. You can
meditate and cause someone's death at
the same time. And the last one, which I
think is [__] hilarious,
charioteering, macha. And that was
supposed to be the learning of command
and purpose under pressure and the
directing of people underneath you. So
these are the six arts of nobility. So
back then, if you wanted a job, you had
to go to an office and the guy goes
"Mhm, but do you know how to shoot
arrows?"
"And macha?"
"Okay.
Do you want to be the task code?"
>> [laughter]
>> And through that he became the
minister of laws or justice in Lu Guo.
Lu Guo is modern-day Shandong, where our
beer is made. The big juicy boys are
from here. You You guys did not come to
work thinking this would be what we were
doing today, huh? I'm so sorry to do
this to you. On V's face, on Ruth's
face, she's not very happy right now
because Confucius is not very appealing
to to straight women. Cuz he's
Cuz his teachings are very, very sexist.
But those weren't his teachings. Those
were later codified in the Han Dynasty
just for the purposes of governance. His
own teachings, we don't know if he even
taught. So uh Kongzi has this
collections of teachings in modern day
called Lunyu. It's translated as
Analects. More colloquially, it means
he's like "Just talk some [__] Just
talk some shit." Because it was a
comprehensive book of all things he
thought about all things. [music] And I
became obsessed with this stupid man
because there's a huge amount of this
[__] collection of thoughts
>> [music]
>> that's just food and why he won't eat
it.
If the [music] cuts are wrong, I won't
eat it. There's a good chance
that he would have denied food if it
wasn't [music] presented properly.
What?
That that that's a nightmare even for
Chinese speakers. And what else?
Even if you have a heavy dank ass meat
sauce it cannot overpower your main
starch like your mashed potatoes and
your rice and [music] your noodles.
That's your shih chi. The one that
pertains most to what we're saying right
now is
He was also very very particular about
the way meat should be before it's
cooked.
Like grain that's sour, meat that's
sour, meat that's old, don't be eating.
That's HACCP. That's good food safety,
right? But then there's a lot of dumb
[__] like
If it smells, if it feels sticky, if it
looks bad, then don't eat it. Makes
sense. If the cook is wrong, I won't eat
it. If it's not medium rare, I don't
want it. If I ordered medium rare and
it's half a degree over, [__] you, I'm
not eating it. So this guy was kind of a
[__] He would have been impossible to
eat with. But there's a very real chance
that this was not his real personality
and people later in life used their at
the time modern opinions to reframe him
as a useful literary and governing
device to control common people. So the
theory in modern China is that this meat
sauce, zha jiang mian, which is now
essentially a ragu, a heavily flavored
meat sauce enjoyed all across the
country but mostly in northern China, is
his favorite food because it essentially
demonstrates all of the aspects of food
that he enjoyed the most. Properly cut,
good balance, fresh, not too sweet, not
too salty, very harmonious. So, this is
why today I'm going through the trouble
of cutting everything into gay little
chunks because I have a feeling that if
I didn't do this, he wouldn't eat it.
So, we're going to do different cuts of
meat. By the way, I once again, I'm
going to be a apologizing a lot
throughout this video. Like if you guys
are bored, feel free to just click to
the part of this video where it's just
the recipe. We have a lot to get
through. Confucius is not something that
we can talk about in one episode
cleanly. I'm just trying my best to give
you the information that I think is
pertinent to the food aspect of his
life.
That's a funny thing. Lotsa, we can do
an episode on Lotsa later if you want.
There's actually a crossover episode
where Confucius and Lotsa met, which is
not true, but it is like a crossover
like it's like Marvel and DC.
>> [laughter]
>> Like Marvel and DC, and they just
philosophied at each other. Confucius
what up? Hey, pusha pusha pusha. He was
like talk with that.
>> [laughter]
>> They just traded. They traded their
classics at each other. So,
if you want to talk about what we know
about Confucius,
first of all, couldn't hold down a job.
No market No market for a man like him
because he was for all intents and
purposes an idealist. He was
uncompromising. He believed in a certain
ideal, and the ideal being that if you
are born, you're either man, woman, old,
young, highborn, lowborn, but you are
born to have a job in life. If you just
stick to your station, then all things
will be fine. So, fathers have a
responsibility to take care of their
sons, and sons have a responsibility to
honor their fathers. And if you just do
that, we'll be okay. However, back then,
no nobody liked that because as a
governor, you want to be able to extract
wealth from your peasants without taking
care of them. So, it didn't catch on
until much later when we codified his
teachings in school and made him part of
standardized testing. For example, his
first job was in Lu Guo as the Da Si
Kou. And he quit because, and I'm not
lying here, because the neighboring
rival state of Qi sent him 80 strippers.
Search it up.
How do we collapse our rivals?
Let's just hit him with some [__]
Let's hit him with some [__] [__]
And then
just stopped governing and started
[__] and looking at titties. And
Confucius said, "This is too unserious.
I'm leaving." And then he went on tour,
14 years touring. He went to Chen Guo,
Cai, Chu, Wei, and essentially
everywhere he went, he was rejected or
shot down because he was just too much
of an idealist.
You're trying to find Confucius' only
fans?
Yeah. 80 hoes.
Timo, how would you explain the concept
of Shi Shu and Xu Shu?
Chinese culture and history is [__]
[__] Do you want to make some food
first?
Yeah.
Make some food first. All right. So,
here's the recipe part, and as we're
making this recipe, there will be more
[__] okay? I'm I'm not even halfway
done the [__] But, let's talk about
the food. Because remember when we did
the in the episode on uh The Jews! And
everyone's like, "No, I want to hear
your bullshit." So, let's [__]
Let's see how much they mean it.
In the wok goes a spoon of oil. For you
to cook this really hard would be not
very tǐng zǔ of you. We have to cook on
a medium low heat the whole time [music]
because all about things in moderation
and balance. So, into a medium-low-ish
wok goes first my chopped up and cubed
pork belly. And we're going to from this
with minimum color
extract some pork fat. Now, keep in mind
everything that we've said today about
our man Confucius is all well and good,
but after his 14-year old tour of all
the countries that didn't want him, he
ended up back in his home of Lu Kuo and
he just became a teacher. He wanted to
become a teacher. On the way he went
through some pretty big [__] There
was this I think it was like Chen Tsai
Kuo chih chien. There was a period he
was just wandering around and he had
such a [__] life that he wrote one of
the most famous quotes about himself. He
described himself as a Sang Chia Chih
Chuan, a stray dog without a home, which
whenever you go, "Oh,
damn."
And then there was like an episode of
his life on tour where his arch nemesis
tried to kill him. So, long story short,
yeah, this guy had a bad life. And then
he came home and started teaching.
He was so
[__] broke that he would teach for
dried meat. Tzu Hsing Chih Yu Chih
Shang.
Wu.
Ni shih hsiu erh shih yu?
Hsiu pa. There you go. [__] yeah. I I
remember I remember I had this argument
cuz I thought it was something else,
too. And then some guy who read a book
with, "No, it's hsiu." Because that's
that's how you prove that you're
educated in Chinese is that you know an
obscure word.
It means life. It's 10 beef jerkies. 10
beef jerkies. Bring me 10 beef jerkies
and I'll teach you how to philosophy.
>> [laughter]
>> [__] [snorts] Chinese, man.
Oh my god. So, yeah, the dude would
teach for beef jerky. He was not a
serious guy. I want to make sure that
all of the quotes that we've said so far
are not wrong. [music]
Cuz this is hard. Like I for people who
don't have a frame of reference, feel
free to ask and in the comments just
comment, like, subscribe. In the comment
section, comment, like, subscribe.
There's going to be Chinese people who
probably know more than us, or most
likely different flavors of Chinese
speakers from different parts of the
world, will all have their own very
specific understanding of Confucius and
what they remember. From Japan to Korea
to China to Vietnam to Cambodia to Latin
America, wherever you see people that
roughly look like this, there is some
Confucius teaching and thought. And we
will all have our own very different
understandings and memories.
>> [music]
>> So, where there's going to be a lot of
junzi arguing down there. How to
translate
junzi?
Scholar, there's no clean translation.
It was a combination of scholar, noble,
and gentleman. These are the These three
concepts put together.
All right. So, you want to sauté until
very blonde and you smell the porkiness.
You want the fat to still look like it
has liquid in it, which is this murky
fat, not fully clear. You want this to
be steam, not smoke.
Now, this might not apply to your pork
if you're in North America, but this
should smell
brothy, like pork bone stock, like
ramen. It should not smell like a roast.
You don't want it to smell like a roast.
You want it to smell like a bowl of
soup. So, this is what you want. Just
crispy on the outsides, just exactly no
more water in the fat.
A well-made zha jiang mian aligns up
perfectly with his ethos. Everything
chopped into gay little chunks. Oh, no,
[__] That's not very Confucius. It's
smoking.
All right, this is
This is the perfect zha jiang mian.
Remember, for those of us that are
Western, once you start making Asian
food reliably and consistently, you'll
realize that one of the
the concepts that you will struggle most
with
is not to over color everything you
make.
As a western food cook, you'll want to
sear everything and my art the [__] out
of it and make it brown and snappy
crisp, which is not wrong. It won't make
this sauce taste poorly, but it will
have sure because the on Chinese food
rarely ever involves hard long sears. So
the original milky fat in the pan. Now
in this gently heating pork fat goes
and you want a lot of ginger but finely
chopped for this because traditionally
speaking these are the two ingredients
that unporkify your pork. Balance that
funkiness of dead animal.
So you want to cook this very gently. In
the west this would be called sweating.
Now in to the pan goes the two favorite
sauces of the north, fermented soybeans.
Uh a very ancient sauce if not one of
the most ancient that we still use today
in modern cookery. It [music] hasn't
changed much.
Essentially it's like the garum of
Chinese cooking which is kidding me
which is one of the components of hoisin
sauce. I think we already did an episode
on that, right? The Lee Kum Kee episode.
I don't know if you will have seen it
already but you can go check that out if
you feel like it and we're going to keep
frying it until the sound changes from
hissing
to slightly frying.
The color goes gently darker and you
smell the roastiness. Now while this is
happening, you can also enjoy putting in
a little bit of meth some Chinese meth.
It will darken because of the sugars in
the down and the proteins coloring
inside the soybean sauce
and this largely replaces the need to
sear your meat so hard. Because
remember, brown things roughly taste the
same whether it be chocolate or coffee
or roast meat. Once it gets to a certain
level of golden brown and [__]
the roastiness is [music]
the underlying common denominator of all
these different foods. So instead of
searing your meat off heavy, we're just
giving it a dark roast heavy sauce.
Gives you the same kind of umami you
Pay, pay, pay. The same roasty delicious
flavors without having to stand over a
pot and sear and smoke up the place.
Keep on smelling and then once you feel
in your Confucian soul that it hasn't
shied away, then you can put in your
pork.
Okay. Now, I want you to smell this pan.
Does it smell
pleasant?
Really, that's the only way to judge if
this is the correct ratios. Of course,
you can also taste a piece of meat.
Judge it based on that. Now, here's a
side note. Classically speaking,
this is not a heavy sauce.
If you're making it at home, it's meat
forward, very balanced, very rich, very
gently roasty in its flavor profile.
Very similar to the proper way to make a
ragù alla bolognese.
But, as time has gone by and this dish
has
gone across oceans and traveled and been
modernized, even in China today, if you
get this at a takeout or a street side
stall, it's very dark and umami and rich
and heavy because these are much cheaper
than meat. I myself prefer a light
sauce, but it's up to you. Now, here's
something that I do that not everyone
does. I like two flavors of my sauce. I
like fresh huang dou jiang and fresh
tian mian jiang as well as roasty. So,
what I do is at this stage of cook, when
this mixture splits fat again, I add a
second dose of tian mian jiang and a
second dose of huang dou jiang. Very
similar to how you might add fresh
tomatoes into your ragù at the end to
give it some more fresh tomato flavor.
Now, at any Asian grocer's, you will be
able to find these two sauces and
they're usually dirt cheap. So, don't
worry about it, right? Now, next would
be tiao just to balance out the the
huīnjìng, the the meatiness of this
dish. What was his quote about how he
can drink a lot, he doesn't pass out?
Yeah, sure. Thousands of years ago, and
also scholar and philosopher, but also
dude from Chengdu. It's like how it's
saying like a lot of inventors came from
Manchester in the UK, but also they're
from Manchester in the UK, which means
they were probably pissed the whole
time, right? All right, now in goes some
water, and the water in this dish is
just there to help it provide a little
bit more time to cook, become
amalgamated, and then once it's the
thickness you like, you can serve. If I
had to guess, perhaps with a bowl of
rice or very simple noodles. Bowl of
rice more likely, because like the bits
are the same size as the bits of meat,
and that's more harmonious, but it also
could have been noodles. It's entirely
up to you. The point is it's [__]
lǔròu. Just serve it on whatever you
want to serve it on. This is Chinese
sloppy joes, philosopher's sloppy joes.
You serve it with a burger bun if you
want. Doesn't really matter. All right.
Oh, no.
Okay, I don't have the patience. By the
way, just as a frame of reference for
anybody who's actually interested, and I
do hope there are some of you, don't
feel the need to actually learn the
quotes
that we've been talking about today.
That's just for a systematic education
in China. If you want, learn the
purposes behind it, and then make your
own translation that makes it easy to
memorize for you in whatever language
you speak, because nobody speaks Chinese
like that. No one's going to look at me
cutting these cucumbers like, "Yo, you
make good job." You make good job when
you show. No one's going to say it like
that. All right, so this is when the
cook is over for me.
When the fats and the sauce have
completely emulsified, and you get this
stickiness, but not sludginess. All
right, are you ready for a bowl of
noodles, my friend? And we're going to
take a little bit of our dòuyá, mung
bean sprouts. They're healthy and
provides a little bit of texture. This
is also harmonious because it looks like
the shape of noodles.
Today's garnishes are blanched bean
sprouts and cucumber strips. I'm going
to put them into a migay little mise en
place tray. All right, cool. We're
ready. Time for noodles. Now, these are
fresh noodles, so they will cook within
30 seconds. And now, I'm going to pull
out
the portion that I want.
Now, on this
goes a very junzi portion, all right?
Super yin, super yang, and a nice thick
ladle of sauce. But, remember,
>> [music]
>> so not too much, you know?
And that is a very classical meat ragu
dish on noodles. Healthy,
good vegetables, a lot of fiber.
If you're afraid of the fat, use leaner
cuts or leaner ground pork. But, other
than that, this is a beautiful dish.
So, time to do a little bit of pulley
pull. Go into the bottom, dig up to This
is the exact effect that [music] I want.
I want every strand of noodle
to have a bountiful, but not obsessive
amount of sauce on it, right? Balance.
Balance above all else. But, also, if
you're a normal person,
>> [laughter]
>> a little bit of unbalanced.
Mhm.
It's a classic for a reason. The
sweetness, the savoriness, the
roastiness, the pork, the textures of
the bittiness. You don't want it to be
fully tender. Remember, you want layers
of texture. So, mid-cooked pork,
bouncy noodles, raw cucumbers, gently
blanched mung bean sprouts. It's very
simple. Remember, we've been talking a
lot of [__] but if you were to just put
your head down and cook like a normal
person, this entire process takes like
15 minutes, top to bottom, and you have
a ragu on the table. You have spaghetti
and meat sauce on the table. Spaghetti
and meat sauce chineza. Ragula ragu ala
Confucius.
Oh.
[__]
All right. Thank you so much for
watching today, guys. I'm so sorry about
the [__] but we are testing. So,
we're going to see if we want to
definitively go in the [__] and
history direction or the food direction.
So, the next episode we're going to be
making
uh sheng jian bao. It's not even that.
But, we're just going to be talking
about the techniques, [music]
brief history, but mostly techniques.
And see which numbers do better. All
right? So, remember comment, like,
subscribe, and let me know what you want
to see. Uh talk often, talk soon.
>> [laughter]
>> If you really think about it, Confucius
was the first Chinese
historical figure
to democratize learning.
He privatized learning. He made learning
something you could pay for and then
expand upon on your own time, which is
pretty serious. Like, he took money to
teach, which is not and not much. He got
paid beef jerky. So, like, he's just
like, "Uh [__] Hey, what do you have?
So, just give me that shit."
Anyways, [__]
Mhm, yeah. Li Zhi Yong.
Ke Wei Gui.
>> [laughter]
>> [__] Mhm, like you chao wu lei. [__]
Fei Li Wu Tian. Fei Li Wu Shi.
Fei Li Wu Yan. Fei Li Wu Dong.
>> [laughter]
>> Just
just
chow and turkey and teaching and just
being a straight guy the whole time.